Hi, I'm Chris.
>> Hi, I'm Trinh.
Nice to meet you.
>> Nice to meet you too.
Are you a software engineer?
>> No, actually,
I'm a technical recruiter at Udacity.
>> Cool, I actually really like Udacity.
I'm taking a number of
Udacity's online courses.
You guys have really helped
me learn at my own pace.
And I love that I have
a flexible learning time.
>> That's really awesome to hear.
Which projects have you been working on?
>> So I actually recently
was building an application.
That let's teachers share
student responses anonymously.
And it's been going really well.
I'm trying to actually
add in graphic UL.
Which is a fairly recent technology.
So that way I can query
the data a little bit easier.
>> It's actually pretty funny that you
mentioned working on an app like that.
Because Udacity is looking into
developing something similar.
>> Very cool!
Could I get your card?
>> Yeah, of course.
I'd really love to hear from you.
So send me an email after this mixer.
>> Great, thanks so
much, nice to meet you.
>> Nice to meet you, too.