Hello and welcome to yet another lesson in our freelancing journey.
We have come a long way since we started.
So far, we've talked about how to find clients,
what are the different avenues to find them,
and how to get a client's project by sending an expression of interest to them.
How to finalize a project scope and also pricing
structures before we start work on a client's project.
Now this lesson is about real work.
The real work that we do for the client.
So far, all our preparation has been for this work.
Here we'll talk about best practices and
strategies of how we can manage the client's project effectively.
How can we deliver our best to the client,
as well as keep the client on the same page while doing that.
First, we'll start with best practices to manage projects effectively.
We will talk about aligning priorities with the clients,
emphasize the need of a conscious communication and how to work efficiently.
Then we'll have a discussion on professionalism and its benefits.
We'll then talk a bit more detail about
the project management tools available out there,
their positives and negatives and
specifically go through one specific tool called Trello,
which you can use to manage projects or even small tasks.
Finally, we'll be talking about
an edge case of what to do when a scope creep happens in a project.
Lastly, we'll do a quick review of what we learned in the lesson overall.
At the end of the lesson,
we'll be able to use best practices and strategies to manage client projects effectively.
We'll also be able to adopt effective communication strategies and
tools to keep the client on the same page while you're working on the project.