Let's get started with learning all about agile.
This lesson will focus on the following;
the Agile mindset and value-driven delivery benefits of agile.
You will be able to differentiate between doing
Agile versus being agile by the end of this lesson.
As mentioned earlier, this lesson will focus on
the Agile mindset and how it sets the tone for being agile versus just doing Agile.
The Agile Manifesto and how it is seen as the foundational set of
four paired core values and
12 principles that sets the foundation for all Agile frameworks.
We will also compare Agile versus
the more traditional Waterfall approaches to product development.
We will wrap up the lesson with an important discussion
on common misconceptions about Agile.
By the end of this lesson,
you will be able to explain
the Agile mindset and value-driven delivery benefits of Agile.
That's going to be great because you will be able to explain to others why
Agile is so great for complex product development.
Differentiate between doing Agile and being agile.
I hope you won't see a lot of people doing Agile rather than being Agile.
But if you do, you'll know it
and you'll be able to guide the team in the right direction.
Explain the Agile Manifesto's four paired core values,
which will set the tone for everything you do in Agile.
Identify and apply the 12 principles of the Agile Manifesto and know here to apply them.
Differentiate between Agile and Waterfall approaches,
and where each makes sense.
Let's get started with learning all about Agile.