This exercise has two parts.
First, you are asked to look at the paired core values and identify
which two particularly stand out as being absent at SocialKare.gov.
Second, you are asked to consider the Agile Principles and identify
which of the 12 Agile Principles would have been beneficial to adopt at Socialkare.gov.
Your answers might be different, but here are mine.
The first missing paired core value from
the Agile Manifesto is individuals and interactions over processes and tools.
Despite heavy government mandated processes,
the lack of team cohesion and a siloed approach to delegating work,
with an autocratic management style impeded the quality of the results.
Then demotivated and fatigued team produced a subpar set of project deliverables.
Working software over comprehensive documentation was also missing.
Despite the paper trail,
a lot of the documentation was ineffective.
No demos for a working prototype were presented,
so there was no early and regular feedback.
The tangible results were inadequate at the end,
the feedback loop was broken with no opportunity for early feedback.
The first missing principle I noticed is simplicity,
the art of maximizing the amount of work not done, is essential.
At SocialKare.gov, we can see that an unnecessarily heavy and,
unprioritized set of requirements forced
the team to work on non-value added requirements.
This lack of an agiled mindset added muda or waste to the results.
The second missing principle is,
our highest priority is to satisfy
the customer through early and continuous delivery of valuable software.
This was clearly missing at SocialKare.gov.
With no delivery of functionality
incrementally and no periodic product demos during the project lifecycle,
SocialKare.gov services and capabilities were not formally able to
be verified and validated until the project was in its last phase.
This delayed the feedback loop.
It also left the business users and ultimately the end-users unsatisfied.
This principle would have encouraged a team to utilize
demos and other feedback loops to get
working features in front of the business users for
early feedback and make it shippable for release on demand.
Another missing principle, is welcome changing requirements even late in development.
Agile processes harness change for the competitive advantage.
We can see evidence that this principle was
missing because requirements or functionality were changing
even at the tail end of the project and
changes had to go through a stringent change control review.
That resulted in delays responding to functional change requests.
A more adaptive change management approach in an Agile environment would have
allowed for a more change-embracing approach with fewer hurdles and fewer delays.
Also, the team is missing.
The business people and developers must work together daily throughout the project.
We can see this because the development team did not actively
engaged those business users who best understood the needs of the end-users.
This resulted in a delayed feedback loop and a lack of team confidence.
Had this happened, the early feedback loop would have
allowed business users to provide valuable insight.
The developers would also have felt more confident and
motivated in knowing that the direction they were heading in was the right one.
These are the missing principles that I identified.
Did you see these or did you find any others?
As an agilist, you'll want to make sure that your team
follows the Agile Manifesto principles as much as possible.