In this section, we will differentiate between Agile and Waterfall approaches.
We will discuss the benefits of Agile over Waterfall,
and we will even explain when Waterfall is a better approach than Agile.
The Waterfall model is a more stringent and process-driven style,
where the project is broken down into project activities through
structured phases with toll gates established to formulate review progress.
In Waterfall, each phase typically depends on the deliverables of the previous one.
The focus is on the work to be done and not delivering functional vertical slices.
Waterfall is quite common for elements of high capital expenditure engineering projects.
Waterfall fixes the scope and estimates time and cost.
Agile breaks this paradigm,
because Agile fixes time and cost,
and allows scoped to be flexible.
Product development life-cycle is an iterations
versus product development life-cycle is divided into strict,
distinct phases, an incremental approaches is used versus a sequential design process.
Agile embraces change versus a stringent in more formal change management approach.
In Agile, a product mindset is
used where the product satisfies the needs of its customers and
adapts per the customers priorities versus
a project mindset with focus completely on accomplishing the project.
In Agile, small dedicated teams with
a high degree of cross-functional collaboration exist,
versus the Waterfall world,
where team coordination and synchronization is limited.
In Agile, product owners with the Agile team prepare the requirements incrementally.
Whereas in the Waterfall world,
business analysts prepare requirements before the product development begins.
The Agile team is self-directed and self-organized,
whereas in the Waterfall world,
the project manager directs and manages the product team.
The Stacey diagram is a popular method to select
the appropriate project or product management style.
Essentially, if there is a lack of agreement and
clarity in terms of both the requirements and as well as process,
then an Agile approach will not magically help with such chaos,
where there is no clear vision and no road map.
Now, when there is near certainty on both the requirements and process upfront,
then there may not be as much value in utilizing
Agile principles because there isn't much need for iterative learning and adapting.
Agile works best in an environment of complexity and some uncertainty,
where an adaptive approach is needed to deliver maximum value.
Agile is also useful in delivering
valuable results when working with complicated requirements.
They need iterative cycles to understand that genuine needs of the end users.
Agile is not a magical solution for chaos.
That is, it cannot be recklessly bring value
to an environment where there is no vision and no clear road map.
Again, Agile also does not really make a lot of sense for simple,
predictable projects and products where the need for
iterative learning and adapting is of no value.