In this exercise, we asked you to look at the weaknesses of
the waterfall approach to the Socialcare.gov project.
You are asked to identify
at least two weaknesses and explain why you see them as weaknesses,
when compared to the Agile approach for Socialcare.gov.
Let's look at my solution.
The first weakness of waterfall planning is thorough documentation and paper trails.
We can see that this is a weakness because instead of
focusing on actual working solutions of value to end users,
the team spent a significant amount of time on
creating and maintaining project documents.
That meant, the team lost focus on working solutions,
and time was taken away from valuable product development.
An Agile approach would have ensured that the focus remains on working solutions,
as opposed to thorough documentation.
The other weakness I identified is that
the testing process started once development was over.
We can see this because all testing was planned and
conducted only after the development of the project was completed.
As a result, bugs were found later in development where they are expensive to fix.
An Agile approach would have included testing in each iteration.
This would have ensured built-in quality.
These are the problems I found.
Did you identify any other issues with the team using a waterfall approach?