As Agile becomes more accepted by the market,
I continue to see a number of detrimental anti-patterns and
misconceptions that are preventing organizations from truly realizing the value of Agile.
I'm going to share five of the ones I see as more common that can
relatively easily be rectified if the Agile mindset is kept in focus.
Misconception number 1, scheduling Agile Ceremonies makes a team Agile.
Just holding Agile Ceremonies,
such as daily stand-ups and retrospectives does not equate to a team becoming Agile.
The ceremonies are a vital part of virtually all Agile Frameworks,
but just holding them for the sake of it does not necessarily deliver any benefits.
In order for an Agile Team to realize the gains from ceremonies,
it is important to adhere to the core principles of Agile.
I see many organizations continue to have
managers in these ceremonies who continue to be directive,
which kills the opportunity for collaboration, self-direction, and self-organization.
Misconception number 2, the facilitator role is filled by a traditional Project Manager.
While leaders will acknowledge
the valuable role of facilitator in any Agile Framework place,
such as the Scrum Master and Scrum.
In reality, many a times
this facilitator role continues to be a traditional project manager.
The reason this is a challenge for many leaders with the right intention,
is that this facilitator role generally does not
have any equivalent in the traditional project management team structure.
Now, it is entirely possible for
a former traditional Project Manager to
step in and play this facilitator role brilliantly,
but it's certainly requires the Agile Mindset shift.
The facilitator role is absolutely critical.
In many Agile Frameworks,
this role is responsible for facilitating,
coaching and really is the Uber Servant Leader who works with everyone and
anyone to mitigate impediments and
assist in whatever can help the Agile team move forward.
This individual does not and should not manage the Agile team.
This is where I see a lot of organizations struggle when transitioning to Agile.
Misconception number 3, Agile team size
is justified to be larger than Agile Frameworks recommend.
Agile recommend small cross-functional teams to allow for
the nimbleness to remain flexible yet
powerful enough to deliver value in every iteration.
Unfortunately, I see a lot of larger Agile team sizes being blessed by leaders in
organizations that are supposedly moving towards
Agile because they feel that their circumstances are unique.
The problem with teams that are larger than somewhere close to
15 is that it becomes challenging to track everyone's work,
and consolidate it all into
a minimum shippable product at the end of every short iteration.
Misconception number 4, the product backlog is
managed analogous to a traditional requirements document.
Product backlogs can be presented in many forms,
but the one thing that should never be is just a pretty front end for
traditional plan driven and process-driven requirements document.
The product backlog needs to follow an Agile mindset,
which drives us to have a feature breakdown approach with a focus on
customer value streams based on the organization's strategic objectives.
Why it does not sound too dramatic?
I see a lot of organizations transitioning to Agile struggle with
the effort of moving from
a traditional business analysis mindset to having a customer centric approach,
where priorities are truly driven by the business.
This is where an empowered product owner plays a pivotal role.
Misconception number 5,
documentation audit trails for compliance are not important in Agile.
This has got to be one of
the most confusing and inaccurate misconceptions in the industry.
As a result, it causes a lot of concern to
leaders who are looking for important documentation to continue to exist.
While the Agile Manifesto states that Agile teams should provide
more emphasis on completed product results over comprehensive documentation,
this does not by any means equate to no documentation at all.
Adaptive planning in Agile Frameworks push Agile teams to do away with non-value
added or redundant documents and paper trails
that have been created over the years just to meet some requirement.
Agile teams are being asked to challenge themselves to truly
document what is valuable to maintain and sustain the product.
Again, the customer-centric and product-focused thought process is essential here.