In this exercise, we ask you to think about the situation at SocialKare.gov and
outline three recommendations to set in place a more Agile Mindset at SocialKare.gov.
We ask you to take into account the Agile Manifesto in
your recommendation and avoid the negative pitfalls of waterfall.
Let's look at what I came up with.
The first strategy I'd recommend is ensuring management commitment.
Any successful Agile transformation initiative requires a serious management commitment.
This senior commitment ensures
strategic input and support by identifying critical business goals,
providing the necessary realistic support and
resources to meet the established expectations.
As product development progresses,
continuing to receive clear direction from executives on aligning
the product with the organization's strategic goals
can have a significant positive impact.
From a resourcing perspective,
management support ensures that a capable product owner,
facilitator, and Agile team are put together to deliver successful results.
Finally, as a last resort,
senior management can play a critical role in removing significant roadblocks.
The second strategy I'd recommend is to provide the team autonomy by empowering them.
A decentralized decision-making model where timely decisions are
critical for moving the product development forward is needed in Agile environments.
The only decisions that should remain centralized with
senior management are the long-term strategic and financial ones.
Having the right resources on the Agile team,
who are capable decision-makers with cross-functional skills
will help facilitate the decision-making process at SocialKare.gov.
The product owner, facilitator,
and Agile team must be empowered to
become self-managing and collaborative at SocialKare.gov.
The product owner and facilitator will obviously need
to ensure collaboration and involvement of
the stakeholder community at the appropriate times to keep
products on track and outcomes aligned with business needs.
A third success strategy is incorporating adaptive planning with relevant buy-in.
It all begins with an inspiring product vision,
which represents the future state of SocialKare.gov and its product offering.
This future state vision should be created by the sponsors,
with this vision being crystal-clear for the product owner,
the vision drives all other elements of adaptive planning.
The next layer of adaptive planning is a product roadmap.
The roadmap, typically presented visually with a timeline,
outlines a product functionality planned for each time period.
This roadmap will progressively evolve over time.
This is followed by a Release Plan.
If the team has a well-refined set of requirements for the first few iterations,
initial Release Plan should comfortably be able to cover the first 2-3 releases.
This has to be balanced with the need to remain
flexible and adaptable with an Agile mindset.
Planning out in tremendous details too far out is not recommended.
Once a release plan is in place,
Iteration Plan should follow in which SocialKare.gov takes
a prioritized backlog and breaks them
down into iterations with a business priority focus.
Finally, SocialKare.gov could benefit through an informal level of daily planning,
which is a natural fringe benefit of
the daily stand-ups recommended by virtually all Agile Frameworks.
This ensures we're proactively dealing with anything important that comes up.
What strategies did you come up with to make
SocialKare.gov more successful in setting an Agile Framework?