We have covered some key Agile concepts in this lesson.
Hopefully, you will now appreciate while Agile has taken the market by storm.
In this lesson, we covered
some fundamental groundwork for developing our understanding of Agile.
We first learn that Agile is a mindset.
It is essential to be agile and not just do the mechanics of what Agile recommends.
We then went on to cover the Agile Manifesto.
We talked about how the need for Agile grew
organically as a result of experts realizing that there was a gap in
customer value delivery in many projects that
follow the traditional waterfall or process-centric structures.
We discussed the importance of
the four paired core values and their associated 12 guiding principles.
This lesson also talked about the difference between Agile and Waterfall.
The advantages and disadvantages of each were covered to ensure
everyone appreciates that one size does not necessarily fit all projects.
In some instances, Waterfall may still be the optimal approach.
We finished up by talking about some misconceptions of Agile.
If you can avoid such misconceptions,
you will become a valuable member of an agile organization.
Moving on, in the next lesson,
we will dive into the topic of building and evolving successful Agile teams.