Why are forward thinking organizations rabidly adopting Agile?
Why are we seeing that global professional bodies such as
the Project Management Institute or PMI in their PMBOK Guide,
and the International Institute of Business Analysis or IIBA in their BABOK guide,
have incorporated and highlighted the importance of Agile in project management,
business analysis, and other product delivery activities.
In an increasingly interconnected and competitive global market space,
I am seeing Agile being leveraged by successful organizations
across the globe to thrive in today's digital economy.
Agile enables organizations to predictably deliver value
in a world where we are constantly being challenged with volatility,
uncertainty, complexity, and ambiguity.
Organizations that I have seen go through
Agile transformation have benefited from the following.
Faster time to market.
An Agile approach accelerates product development cycles.
According to various studies,
Agile teams are able to release products anywhere from 50-80 percent
faster that teams that continue to
use a more traditional approach to product development.
Early return on investment.
On the ROI front,
Agile helps us accomplish two things: help squeeze cash out of work in progress,
also known as WIP,
and increase project and portfolio returns.
Let's look at each of these.
In Agile, by not allocating funds up front and hampering organizational liquidity,
cash is freed up to more flexibly invest as the product evolves based on market needs.
Waste, commonly referred to as the Japanese term Muda in the real-world,
is reduced by trimming down on unproven assumptions and
mitigating the chances when investing in non-value added features.
That is, features that are of no value and are probably a waste of resources.
This helps a product management team prioritize features more
proactively and steer towards better decisions for product's success.
Agile allows us to fail fast or even stop early.
This allows executives to move funds around
from one project to another at a portfolio level.
Priorities are re-evaluated more frequently and
proactively to maintain a close alignment to the pulse of the market.
As Eric Reis outlines in his book, The Lean Startup,
that early feedback loop from the customer or
a proxy who represents the customer is priceless.
Frequent feedback from the business and end-users ensures
the Agile team is focused on the solutions and intended goals,
and helps ensure they deliver high-value features.
Equally important, feedback loops allow
the team to accommodate change later in the development process,
particularly as newer refined requirements emerge.