Developing and delivering products which customers do not
want and for which there may not be a market can be an expensive adventure.
Agile works to efficiently develop products where
the chances of it being valuable to customers and end users is enhanced.
Agile advocates for ensuring that the product strategy and execution remain aligned.
The heartbeat of Agile is the iterative approach which allows for
adjustments to ensure value-driven items are delivered in short time frames.
The proactive and transparent collaborative communication stands in Agile,
allows for constructive and genuine user and
market-driven insight to ensure the product is heading in the right direction.
Agile helps manage risks more proactively.
By evaluating project progress more frequently,
we are able to meaningfully evaluate during each iteration.
This helps the team measure delivered value,
as well as showcase working product to obtain realistic feedback.
Specifically, risk reduction is accomplished through
iterative deliveries as requirements are discovered,
prioritized, and demoed to representatives from the business,
commonly referred to as business proxies in Agile.
Agile exposes and provides the opportunity to recognize and manage risks early.
Risks are managed through
cross-functional teams that respect and understand each other's skill sets,
sustainable and predictable pace,
continuous feedback, and technical excellence,
that is built-in quality.
This transparency ensures risks are managed early.
Building and delivering high-quality products requires a commitment,
but the business benefits and value delivered justify this investment.
The business benefits from elevated customer satisfaction,
as well as better velocity,
which is essentially a measure of how much valuable work was completed in an iteration.
The business also benefits for
a more predictable pace of the products incremental delivery.
A more reliable solution environment
enables an agile team to confidently innovate and scale.
Agile emboldens the culture by encouraging open communication,
collaboration, and a cohesiveness driven by a common business value-driven goal.
By breaking down silos,
Agile promotes a more adaptable work environment that boost morale,
prevents burnout, and encourages a highly productive, sustainable pace.
When treated with respect,
Agile team members evolve
their practices and find opportunities that benefit the business.
This aspiration is elevated when
Agile teams understand the larger purpose behind their work.