Efficiency and effectiveness.
This is a fine balancing act that Agile recommends.
If you're only focused on going fast, you prioritize efficiency.
But if you are trying to focus on innovation, creativity,
and making sure you're working on the right thing,
you need to focus on effectiveness.
This is often done at the cost of efficiency.
Agile ensures a balanced approach,
whereby Agile teams ensure that there is a balance between speed and creativity.
Agile principles specifically recommend customer satisfaction by delivering
product features and functionality with built-in quality that
offer business value that customer is kept satisfied.
Customer satisfaction is further increased because they're
requested features are delivered not only early in the project life cycle,
but also continuously, as a product has evolved and enhanced based on market feedback.
Agile projects include a product owner who is an individual responsible for ensuring
clear translation of what the customer wants into product requirements.
Agile helps teams keep the vision and focus.
The vision drives what is to be included and
excluded in the list of features and functionality,
which is customarily called a product backlog in Agile.
Agile is the deliberate goal of setting challenging but very realistic expectations,
helps ensure that the business owners needs are being
prioritized and met while effectively managing their expectations.
In Agile, milestones and accomplishments are based on
demonstrable results through the objective evaluation of working systems.
Such demos give the business owners an opportunity to
ensure that the Agile teams work is aligned with the vision.
Agile works well in the development of complex dynamic systems.
For example, self-organizing interactions among the Agile team,
they give rise to outcomes that may be different from or
in addition to any anticipated or targeted outcomes.
The initially unplanned, yet valuable results can emerge in such circumstances.
Agile frameworks are designed to accommodate such emergent needs.
Agile project management includes many practices, tools,
and artifacts to improve predictability,
which helps reduce risk.
Agile's adaptive planning approach is
an iterative approach which organizes several information flows,
analyses, issues, and opinions that
coalesce into predictable decisions that align with the strategy.
For example, successful agile organizations keep the same iteration length,
and Agile team allocation throughout the product development life-cycle.
This ensures some structure within the chaos.
This also enables the project team to predict the exact cost for each iteration.
Let's take another look at the list of reasons why companies are switching to Agile.
I hope you understand now why so many people are excited about Agile.
Today's digitally complex and interconnected business world
is driving organizations to seek avenues to increase speed to market,
meet customer demand, and increase team productivity.
Organizations want to use Agile to get there by
developing products better, faster, and cheaper.