Agile experts, or agilists as we'd like to call ourselves,
adopt a practical and realistic approach to delivering
the best value and quality in the shortest sustainable time.
Agilists take into account an understanding of the economics of delivering products.
In other words, decisions by Agile experts are made within a proper economic context
where we ensure that it makes
financial sense to proceed with developing a particular feature or feature set.
Agile experts also take into account the trade-offs between risks and uncertainties,
as well as operational and development costs.
In other words, a systems thinking approach reinforced by
a growth mindset helps Agile experts deliver optimal business value.
With a traditional mindset,
we look at the pieces of the solution within their separate elements.
But the roots of systems thinking is in systems theory,
which looks at the interdependent and interconnected components of
a system that come together to deliver a solution in a cohesive manner.
Systems thinking takes a holistic approach in which the Agile team looks
at the way a system's components interrelated influence each other,
and how these components come together within
the context of larger systems to deliver a solution.
Systems thinking helps Agile teams see beyond the heart of
a problem to find valuable and sustainable solutions that deliver measurable benefits.
Agile experts appreciate that optimizing a component does not optimize the entire system.
Systems thinking helps Agile teams work to
understand the larger aim of the entire system.
Systems thinking is about seeing the product in
motion through system demos or presentations,
in which the end users get a sense of what the functional experience will actually be,
recognizing that the big picture is rarely static,
but almost always a web of factors that interact to create patterns and change over time.
Systems thinking becomes a catalyst for Agile experts to
catapult the organization's learning and continuous improvement journey.
In a growth mindset,
individuals on a team have the mindset that
their abilities can grow through dedication and hard work.
Agilists give credence to a growth mindset.
They are able to elevate Agile teams to believe that
their most basic abilities can blossom through dedication and hard work.
This view creates a passion for learning and the resilience
that is essential for Agile teams to accomplish astounding results.
This growth mindset is balanced with ethics, principles,
and indeed values that have much to do with concepts enshrined
in corporate governance and corporate social responsibility.
Agilists do not just provide lip service to
high sounding words like integrity, commitment, and respect.
Instead, agilists ensure that
such enduring principles do not get sacrificed in the face of expedience,
thereby ensuring organizations do not resort to pursuing business results at any cost.