Agile significant global adoption is driven by the discovery that the only way for
successful teams to cope with
today's turbulent customer driven marketplace is to become agile.
Agile enables teams and organizations to effectively manage continuous change.
It permits teams to flourish in an environment that is increasingly volatile,
uncertain, complex, and ambiguous,
also known as VUCA.
Volatility is when there are unexpected or unstable
possibilities that may influence the work being done.
Uncertainty refers to the extent to which
an organization can confidently predict or forecast the future.
More uncertainty makes it harder to predict.
Complexity exists when there are
many interconnected parts and variables that influence each other.
Ambiguity refers to a lack of clarity such as not having
a clear understanding of the genuine needs of the customer and then users.
What is agile exactly?
Agile is a set of principles that guide how we as individuals,
as teams, and as organizations think about as well as act upon the work that we do.
Business agility is the ability of an organization to adapt quickly to market changes,
respond rapidly and flexibly to customer demands that make business sense,
as well as adapt and lead the change in
a productive and cost-effective manner with no compromise to quality.
An agile mindset is the set of attitudes supporting an agile working environment.
When we talk about an agile mindset,
we include respect, collaboration, continuous improvement,
iterative learning cycles, mastery and ownership,
focus on delivering value,
and adaptability to change.
Respect is critical for successful teamwork.
At the organizational level,
respect for associates at all levels of the organization, the customer,
and the prioritized product backlog,
which is a prioritized list of work for the Agile team,
which itself is key to delivering excellent products and solutions.
Collaboration is also important.
With increasingly complex systems across functional and scale,
the team is needed to find solutions.
A collaborative approach will decrease the number of
inefficient handoffs necessary to deliver the product.
Continuous improvement is an important built-in quality mindset
where quality is a habitual part of the organization's DNA.
Organizations that support agile teams
firmly believe there's always room for improvement.
Iterative learning cycles allow agile teams to
exhibit and execute on an agile or growth mindset.
This growth mindset is an attitude that turns
apparent failures into growth opportunities for learning.
This ties in with the already discussed belief that agile teams can improve over time,
that our abilities are not fixed,
but rather evolve as new emergent ideas are cultivated.
The ability to develop mastery and having a sense of ownership in the project
deliverables increases the desire to deliver high quality work.
The value-driven delivery perspective ensures
agile teams maintain a customer satisfaction centric culture.
This equates at a minimum to agile teams ensuring that
the customer needs are paramount when focusing on delivering value.
Embracing changes that make
a business value sense is a cornerstone to successful agile teams.
Heavy processes to manage such changes must be tempered to ensure
they do not become an impediment to
enabling changes that make business and economic sense.
The agile mindset cultivates high performing teams,
which in turn deliver quantum value for their customers and business owners.
The agile mindset is the bedrock of being agile.
Some organizations and agile teams unfortunately just focus on doing agile.
This equates to simply adopting
the practices without committing to or exhibiting agile principles and values.
Being agile is the foundation that truly elevates individuals, teams,
and organizations to unleash
their latent potential to deliver monumental and focused value.
Being agile implies living and breathing
agile principles and values through agile practices consistently every day.
The more time I spend with agile initiatives across the world,
the more I realize that understanding this difference
is absolutely vital for successful agile transformations.
When agile teams are being agile,
is a clearly directed sharp focus that gives
everyone a purpose aligned with the organization's vision,
autonomy to self-direct, as well as an opportunity for
cultivating mastery to unleash immense value.