In this exercise, you are asked to identify
at least three anti-type patterns that prevented the agile mindset from being present,
and explain why each anti-pattern is problematic for SocialKare.gov.
While your answers could have been a little different, here are mine;
the project manager did not build an environment of
making the team self-directed and self-organized,
this was evident when each team member worked on
their own list of tasks rather than a shared list.
The project manager monitored everyone's progress
individually rather than looking at team output.
The project manager stepped into
troubleshoot technical problems instead of having the team solve their own problems.
As a result, the team did not get an opportunity to build autonomy
and confidence without relying on the project manager to step into troubleshoot,
and that impacted team morale.
Quality was not built-in iteratively in the product development life cycle.
The evidence for this is that major coding flaws
arose and supporting systems integration testing was patchy.
This resulted in delays going into production,
which frustrated both the business leadership and the end users.
Further, defects and issues were identified after going to production.
Interim working solutions were not presented frequently to
the business and end users for proactive buying an feedback.
The evidence is that the product team did not have
frequent hands-on demonstration on front-end functionality.
The few scattered demos did not have the results vertically sliced, that is,
all the layers of the interim technical solution were not
integrated to present an observable version to users.
This resulted in an incomplete set of features going to production,
complaints started to flow in rapidly,
and the development team had to respond in a reactionary manner,
which is often more expensive,
high-risk, and prone to further mistakes.
Excessive and not so valuable documentation was required by the project,
we can see this because the team created a lot of process driven
documentation to meet the paper trail needs of the government agencies.
Yet despite all this paperwork,
no one raised issues of SocialKare.gov's functionality at the quarterly meetings since
neither business representatives nor end
user representatives had any hands-on demonstration
of functionality that was being built.
Since this was not the right documentation,
oversight was inadequate, a large number of technical and functional issues arose.
The team ended up spending a lot of time creating documents.
This time would have been better spent on building the actual product functionality.
As a result, the product results were disappointing,
clearly indicating that the paper trail was not effective.
There was little in the way of ensuring
these requirements made business sense throughout the project life cycle.
We can see that because
several key requirements were never uncovered until going to production.
It was later realized that several of
these requirements were of little value to end users,
as a result the resource effort put into
lower priority requirements ended up pushing out the higher priority needs.
So those are the anti-patterns I found,
which ones did you identify?
As you spend more time as an aguist,
you'll be able to spot these anti-patterns more quickly.