In order to appreciate the Agile Manifesto,
we need to look at what led it to being created by 17 thought leaders in 2001.
Up until the late 1990s,
majority of product development followed
a waterfall-style project management life cycle
that was based on adhering to strict processes.
Product development teams focused heavily on gathering detailed requirements upfront.
The contract between the development team and
customer became the primary focus of the delivery,
resulting in value taking on a secondary level of importance.
Products started to get more complex with several interconnected pieces,
that got discovered and entangled further down the development pipeline.
This resulted in delays which
further frustrated customers and impacted their bottom line.
To add to the woes,
final product delivery would often have features and functionality
that did not work as expected or anticipated by the customer.
The whole product procedure was process centric with the goal of delivering
the product successfully rather than focusing on delivering a successful product.
This is what led 17 experts to get together and finalize
the Agile Manifesto at a meeting in Utah, back in 2001.
The four agile core values or better
stated as the four paired core values are listed here.
Again, these were developed by 17 industry experts who finalized this in 2001.
Let's walk through each one.
Individuals and interactions over processes and tools.
Agile places more importance and emphasis on people
and their interactions over processes and even tools.
After all, it is the skilled human resources,
when given a purpose, motivation,
and a suitable environment,
who respond to business needs and drive
the development process to successfully deliver a valuable product.
Processes and tools by their very nature are less responsive to change.
Working software over comprehensive documentation.
Documentation requires a time and resource commitment.
A heavy focus on documentation leads to
slower processes that businesses are looking to
mitigate in a market that requires rapid action.
Moreover, some of the documentation can be
redundant and just not as useful to the Agile team,
the business users, or even those looking for
reliable trace of the valuable work being accomplished.
Now, let's be clear here.
Agile is about streamlining, not eliminating documentation.
However, while documentation has its value,
in the Agile mindset,
it is working solutions that are paramount.
Agile clearly states that we get more traction from
working software that can be presented to the business.
Customer collaboration over contract negotiation.
Agile promotes a collaborative outlook when product owners work
with their customers in reaching agreement on the details of the product delivery.
This is in contrast to
traditional project management methodologies in which both sides exhaustively
negotiate requirements for the product in
tremendous detail before the product development work even begins.
Agile in contrast, suggests a more practical approach by including
the customer throughout the life cycle of
the product delivery to ensure continual feedback.
Responding to change over following a plan.
Every Agilist will tell you that Agile embraces change.
When working with a more traditional project management methodology,
changes often have an inefficient and multi-step formal review process.
In such circumstances, changes are often seen as to be avoided since supposedly,
all the requirements were documented,
reviewed, and approved upfront.
However, Agile intentionally works to maximize the power of
progressive elaboration through short iterations
which allows for easier value driven changes.
Agile truly embraces changes that make
practical and business sense as a means to improve a product and add value.
The goal is not to police change request stringently, but rather,
to continue to challenge ourselves to
identify changes that can add additional business value.
The Agile Manifesto is four paired core values drive the 12 Agile principles.