The Agile Manifesto's four-paired core values drive the 12 Agile principles.
Our highest priority is to satisfy the customer
through early and continuous delivery of valuable software.
Let us not forget that the goal of
product development is the development of successful products.
An evolutionary approach to product development works better for complex systems.
Then defining everything upfront before the team starts to develop.
Welcome changing requirements even late in development.
Agile processes harness change for the customer's competitive advantage.
Due to the dynamic competitive landscape,
requirements can and will change throughout product development.
Traditional software developers adopt change
management processes which are designed to prevent or reduce scope creep.
But when you think about it,
these are really unnatural change prevention processes,
not change management processes.
Agile lists embrace change and instead
proposing adaptive or agile change management approach,
which treats requirements as a prioritized backlog,
which is how to get refined over time.
Deliver working software frequently from a couple of weeks to a couple of months,
with a preference giving to the shorter timescale.
Frequent and iterative delivery of
working product provides the business with practical feedback.
This transparency provides an opportunity for the business
and the development team to sync up more frequently in terms of direction,
product goal, and what value is anticipated for the product.
Business people and developers must work together daily throughout the project.
The product owner, who represents the business stakeholders and the Agile team,
adopt practices that ensure inclusive and joint practices,
which enables a product owner to be actively involved with product development.
Build projects around motivated individuals,
give them the environment and support they need and trust them to get the job done.
Agile leaders build Agile teams with skilled resources,
who are willing to work together collaboratively with a growth mindset.
They have the humble and respectful realization that
people are a primary success factor in product development.
The most efficient and effective method of conveying information
to and within a development team is face-to-face conversation.
For a product development team to succeed,
its members must communicate and collaborate effectively.
Face-to-face communication, utilizing a shared information radiator,
such as a shared drawing environment is one effective example.
With increasingly global teams located remotely,
telepresence technology can be leveraged to
build this virtual face-to-face type communication.
Working software is the primary measure of progress.
The primary measure of product development should be the delivery of
working product increments which meet the evolving needs of the business.
Agile processes promote sustainable development.
The sponsors, developers, and users
should be able to maintain a constant pace indefinitely.
A highly skilled team simply just cannot be expected to successfully
develop a product by compelling people to work overtime for extended periods.
Complex technical work is best done at an intense,
yet realistically sustainable pace.
Continuous attention to technical excellence and good design enhances agility.
Built-in quality practices have enormous benefits.
It allows for easier maintenance and scalability of the product, coding standards,
best practices related to refactoring and test development techniques are
some examples of built-in quality practices that are prevalent in strong Agile teams.
Simplicity. The art of maximizing the amount of work not done is essential.
With the guidance or the product owner.
Agile teams focus on high-value activities,
which allows them to focus on the high business value needs.
The lower value items are given a lower priority and only worked on if time permits.
The best architectures, requirements,
and designs emerge from self-organizing teams.
This is a critical principle of the Agile world
to ensure that emerging and effective architectures,
requirements, and designs are built into
the product development life cycle to maximize technical excellence.
At regular intervals.
The team reflects on how to become more effective,
then tunes and adjusts its behavior accordingly.
Finding concrete opportunities for improvement is a continual effort.
Agile embeds techniques such as
retrospectives to ensure continual improvement is followed through upon.
As you can see, the Agile Manifesto is
four-paired core values and its associated 12 guiding principles set
a solid foundation four the various agile frameworks that are currently
being practiced by successful organizations in today's digital age.