Nice to see you again.
This lesson takes a deep dive into Agile frameworks.
It begins with an introduction to Agile frameworks in
general and what the benefits are of an Agile framework.
This includes coverage of the shared characteristics of
Agile frameworks and reasons why adopting an agile framework makes sense.
We then look at Scrum as a framework and how Scrum
can be advantageous to when trying to balance priorities.
Once you get familiar with Scrum,
you will be able to deliver value with
flexibility and patience in a collaborative manner.
This lesson then goes into Kanban as a framework and it's
unique advantage in managing flow and work in progress or WIP.
Finally, a third discussion on XP and its advantages will
follow with an appreciation for its best practices around technical excellence.
By the end of this lesson,
you will be able to identify the advantages of using a framework,
identify the specific and shared characteristics of Scrum,
Kanban and the XP frameworks.
You will also be able to determine which frameworks are appropriate for a given project,
identify the core team roles,
and assign team members to each role,
as well as implement best practices for each framework,
including ceremonies and artifacts.
Let's get going.