In order to minimize wasting time in unnecessary meetings and group discussions,
the Kanban framework recommends focused meetings with a specific purpose.
You remember the six Scrum ceremonies, right?
In Kanban, the ceremonies are simplified.
There is no sprint planning ceremony,
and there is no sprint retrospective,
and the sprint review or demo is just called a review or demo,
so the four Kanban ceremonies align with four of the Scrum ceremonies.
The four Kanban ceremonies are virtually the
same as their counterpart ceremonies in the Scrum framework.
As you can see here,
the project vision ceremony in Kanban has virtually the same purpose,
agenda, timing, as well as expected outcome.
The same can be said for the daily stand up,
as well as the review or demo,
and the same also goes for release planning.
Kanban provides the ability to view in one instance,
the status of the entire product development journey.
The Kanban board makes it very easy to visualize what has been completed,
what is currently in progress,
and what work items have not commenced yet.
Since it focuses on the Agile team's workflow and throughput,
Kanban is seen as a better Agile Framework option solution for projects where
the work is likely to involve a large quantity of relatively small activities.
Kanban is also suitable for work that may arise on an ad-hoc basis.
Now, let us discuss Kanban roles and artifacts.
Much like the various Agile Frameworks,
there are three core roles in the Kanban framework as well.
The first is a product owner or PO,
who is seen as the voice of the customer,
the next key role is that of the facilitator,
and then we have the Agile team.
Let's look at all three of these important roles.
Kanban has a much more flexible approach,
but two key recommended artifacts are the Kanban board and cumulative flow diagram.
A Kanban board plays a valuable role since it
articulates the work items in the various stages of the product developing journey.
With a cumulative flow diagram,
problem areas are easily detected,
changes could be made so that work can continue efficiently,
and accumulative flow diagram also shows the total amount
of WIP or work in process and how quickly projects are being completed.