Let's look at the important characteristics of the XP framework.
Extreme programming, which is routinely referred to XP is in the industry,
is a powerful Agile framework with its roots in software development.
XP has a strong focus on technical excellence and best practices in software development.
Now, let's look at the XP core values.
There are five XP core values.
They are; simplicity, communication,
feedback, courage, and respect.
Let's discuss each one of these XP core values.
XP encourages reducing unnecessary complexity when building a solution.
Minimizing extra features is also encouraged in XP since it
reduces waste and maximizes value for the investment.
Simplicity, just like all the XP core values stems from the Agile manifesto.
In an XP environment,
all the team members have transparency in being aware of
what is expected of them in terms of deliverables,
as well as being aware of what others in the team are contributing towards.
A reliable avenue for keeping everyone informed is the daily stand-up,
which is a pivotal communication tool in XP.
Feedback in every iteration is taken seriously in XP,
with an opportunity to demonstrate working results early and often.
Failing fast allows the team to make changes proactively to improve the product.
Courage, allows a team to bravely tell the truth about progress,
estimates and any impediments to value delivery.
Paired programming and XP core practice that will be explained shortly,
requires that courage of paired team members to share code
and valiantly adapt to adhere to shared coding standards.
Respect is a key foundational element in XP for a high-achieving team.
In XP, each team member is accountable for a successful product delivery,
which requires giving everyone respect to
accomplish their own tasks while working collaboratively.
Respect is practiced in pair programming as well,
where paired team members respect their differences.