These five core values in XP,
set the tone for XP's 13 core practices.
Let's proceed to look at XP's 13 core practices.
XP, which was created by Kent Beck,
has 13 core practices that are highly recommended to be followed.
The whole team practice encourages
the entire XP team to be co-located when practically possible.
Collaboration tools can be leveraged to follow the whole team practice for remote teams,
XP encourages role blending where T-shaped skills are exhibited.
This allows for optimal utilization of resources.
The whole team practice also allows for
efficient flow of information between team members.
Planning games is really just another name for planning.
XP has two main planning ceremonies.
They are release planning and iteration planning.
Small and frequent releases are encouraged in
XP at both the iteration as well as release level.
Built-in quality is ensured in these small deliverables by
leveraging best practices such as continuous integration.
In the customer tests practice,
the product owner works with the customer to describe
one or more test criteria as part of defining the requested functionality.
The team then ideally builds automated tests to
confirm that the developed products acceptance criteria are met.
In XP, multiple team members can work on the same code.
So no single person owns a piece of work.
This strengthens the product with a broader knowledge of the code across the team,
quality is also enhanced.
Further, from a risk mitigation perspective,
it reduces the risk of loss of knowledge if a team member departs.
Everyone in the team codes to a consistent standard in XP.
Ideally, the code should look as if it is homogeneously written under a uniform standard.
XP advocates for a sustainable pace.
The highest level of productivity can only be maintained at a sustainable pace.
So several weeks of overtime for the team are
both counterproductive as well as unsustainable.
According to the XP framework,
optimal delivery of long-term value requires a sustainable rate.
In XP, it is important to adhere to a set of easy to remember
standard naming conventions for items such as variable names,
class names, and methods.
This facilitates communication and avoids confusion.
This also ensures everyone understands the terms clearly during product development.
Software builds are regularly integrated by combining all the coding components
together to verify that it compiles and works as a collective code base.
This is typically done several times a day.
Integration keeps all team members on the same page because it brings to
light any issues before further code is built upon faulty work.
In Test-driven development, also known as TDD,
the team writes the acceptance test before the actual coding is done.
Each small release is thoroughly tested prior to being released to production.
While this appears to take more time upfront,
it allows for a much cleaner application in the long run.
Each team member in XP works to improve the design of
existing code without affecting any of the functionality or external behavior.
This keeps the design cleaner to maintain and makes it easier
to develop new functionality on top of the existing code base.
The optimal design is the simplest one that works.
A recommended design in HP is one that successfully
runs all the tests and delivers a desired business value.
In Agile product delivery,
requirements are expected to evolve and change.
So XP proposes to only do what is needed to meet current requirements.
XP advocates team members to work on product deliverables in pairs.
The data shows that this practice produces
higher quality code and costs less in the long run.
Another key benefit is that knowledge is shared across the team.
Again, here are the 13 XP core practices.