As you must have noticed,
XP has a much more stringent approach than many other Agile frameworks.
For example, as we discussed earlier,
Kanban is a much lighter framework with plenty of room for flexibility in the processes.
None other practices in XP are
optional and the practices are very specific about how the work gets done.
XP again, is strongly oriented to software development.
The XP framework has four core roles,
three of which are quite analogous to the three core roles in most Agile frameworks.
The first is the customer,
which is somewhat like the P0.
The customer is the business representatives.
The next role is the tester.
Testers are primarily responsible for quality assurance.
Another role is that of the coach who acts as a mentor for the team.
The coach is also a facilitator for the team.
Then we have programmers who are the developers who built a product.
Let's look at all four of these important roles.
A customer is a critical role in XP,
since the customer is responsible for working with the business to
prioritize and maximize the value of the product deliverables being worked on.
The customer is primarily responsible for prioritizing and managing the Product Backlog.
An XP team has a small number of programmers who work together and
collaborate in practicing XP core values like paired programming,
Test-driven development, as well as continuous Integration.
A high achieving XP team will include a designer,
one senior programmer, and an architect,
under the programmer role.
Programmers exhibit T-shaped skills by assisting with testing when time permits.
The XP coach is a servant leader and
plays a pivotal role supporting in the team's success.
XP has several detailed practices,
which the coach helps the team to learn and follow.
Testers partner with, and assist the customer in creating acceptance criteria,
execute test cases, and communicate the outcomes and feedback with the programmers.
All the XP ceremonies aligned with
the Scrum Framework ceremonies that we discussed earlier,
except the names are different.
In XP, they are Iteration Planning,
Iteration Review, and Iteration Retrospective.
The six XP ceremonies are virtually the
same as their counterparts ceremonies in the Scrum Framework.
As you can see here,
the project vision ceremony in Kanban has virtually the same purpose,
agenda, timing, and expected outcome.
The same can be said for the daily standup in XP,
as well as XP's Iteration Planning.
The Iteration Review and Demo,
in XP also follows the same format.
Iteration Retrospectives remain just as critical in XP as they are in Scrum,
Kanban, and other Agile frameworks.
The release planning session in XP is also the same as in other Agile frameworks.
Since XP is the most thorough Agile framework in terms of processes,
all the artifacts covered in the Scrum Framework and Kanban Framework are included in XP.
Again, XP is considerably more structured in
the Scrum Framework and a lot more thorough than the lightweight Kanban framework.