In this exercise, you are asked to identify key differences between Kanban and XP.
You are asked to cover the roles,
the respective ceremonies, as well as the practices.
Here are my responses.
The three core roles in the Kanban framework are the PO,
the facilitator, and the Agile team.
Let's start with the facilitator role.
This role is responsible for providing Kanban framework coaching and guidance,
facilitating the Agile teams work and protecting it from problems.
The facilitator is a servant leader to the PO and Agile team.
The next core role in Kanban is the product owner.
The product owner is specifically known as the voice of the customer.
This is the one individual who is responsible for
the prioritized work item list called a product backlog.
The product owner shares business decisions in a timely manner and provides
any requirements or functionality related information
to the Agile team in a timely manner.
The next core role in Kanban is the Agile team member.
This core role would primarily include developers,
who are responsible for the creation and delivery of a system.
However, all other Agile team members will also be included in this category.
This includes, but is not limited to,
those who will conduct modeling, programming,
testing, front end design,
business analysis, release activities, and others.
The XP framework has four core roles,
three of which are quite analogous to the Kanban roles that we just discussed.
The first is the customer,
which is somewhat like the PO.
The customer in XP,
is the business representative.
The next core role in XP is the tester.
Testers are primarily responsible for quality assurance.
This role does not explicitly exist as a separate role in Kanban.
Another role is that of the coach who acts as a mentor for the team.
Since the coach is also a facilitator for the team,
this is somewhat similar to the facilitator role in Kanban.
Then we have programmers who are the developers who build the product.
While not exactly the same,
this is most closely related to the Agile team member role in Kanban.
Let's look at all four of these important roles.
An XP team has a small number of programmers who work together and
collaborate in practicing XP core values like pair programming,
test-driven development, as well as continuous integration.
A high achieving XP team will include a designer,
one senior programmer, and an architect under the programmer role.
Programmers exhibit T-shaped skills by assisting with testing when time permits.
Testers partner with and assist the customer in creating acceptance criteria,
execute test cases, and communicate the outcomes in feedback with the programmers.
Again, this is a role that does not directly exist in Kanban.
The XP coach is a servant leader and plays a pivotal supporting role in the team success.
XP has several detailed practices which the coach helps the team to learn and follow.
A customer is a critical role in XP since the customers are responsible for
working with the business to prioritize and
maximize the value of the product deliverables being worked on.
The customer is primarily responsible for prioritizing and managing the product backlog.
Again, the customer is similar to the PO in the Kanban framework.
There are certain ceremonies in XP that do not need to take place in Kanban.
One is the iteration retrospective where there's
an opportunity for the team to inspect itself and create a plan for improvements.
Team members discuss what went well during the iteration,
as well as opportunities for improvement.
The iteration retrospective occurs once per
iteration and is timebox to three hours per iteration.
The second is iteration planning,
where the work to be performed in the iteration is planned.
The agenda includes creating the iteration backlog,
planning out the tasks,
and estimating at a task level.
This can occur a few times per iteration,
but it's timebox in total to eight hours per iteration.
XP is considerably more stringent.
XP has 13 detailed practices,
whereas Kanban just focuses on flow and Work in Progress or WIP.