A number of organizations, particularly software-centric entities,
get excited when they read that XP brings in
rigor alongside the typical benefits of Agile,
such as visibility, transparency,
and genuine collaboration towards value and delivery.
Yet, I have seen many organizations struggle and get extremely frustrated with XP.
Let's walk through some of the challenges of XP.
XP places a lot of emphasis on software development practices.
This is different from
many other Agile Frameworks in which the emphasis is more on streamlining processes.
Traditional project managers are able to transition into
other frameworks like Scrum more comfortably,
since it feels like a leaner version of project management.
In XP, a traditional project manager might be
required to have a comfort level with stringent software-centric processes.
Recruiting experienced XP coaches is a challenge.
XP coaches are expected to be familiar with intricate details of software development,
as well as have the right personality and temperament to
facilitate ceremonies and difficult conversations.
Such a combination of skills is both rare and expensive.
It is a lot easier to recruit for a Scrum master role in the Scrum Framework.
XP is indeed complex to implement.
So it can feel anti-Agile to some organizations and their leaders.
It takes some patience and discipline to both develop and maintain a successful XP team.
For example, practices like pair programming,
continuous integration, and test-driven development are not the easiest to adapt to.
With 13 defined practices,
XP has considerably more practices in many other Agile Frameworks.
Organizations who are thinking of adopting XP need experienced coaches,
a willing and highly skilled team of programmers,
and leaders who have the resilience to
guide the organization through the initial turbulence.
This will ensure everyone will work together to
align with the organization's vision and mission.