In this exercise, you are asked to select and recommend
a particular Agile Framework for
socialkare.gov taking into account their specific scenario.
You are asked to include
a specific characteristic of the project that makes sense for this Agile Framework,
as well as an explanation or justification for it.
Here my responses, I recommend socialkare.gov to consider adopting the Scrum Framework.
There is a need for time-boxed iterations or sprints,
and the justification is that socialkare.gov is a complex project,
and time-boxed sprints will allow for regular demos and proactive feedback from
the business to ensure that
the project and the product deliverables are heading in the right direction.
This was missing and caused a lot of issues.
There is a need for and tremendous benefit with Retrospectives.
Sprint Retrospectives will ensure the Agile team at socialkare.gov is working towards
guided continual improvement to help
such a complex project successfully delivered the anticipated business value.
Otherwise, the danger of losing the focus on
business value is eminent in such an intertwined project.
Socialkare.gov has a need for self-directed and self-organized teams.
Now, the Scrum Framework insists on the Agile team being given
autonomy to work on the prioritized and assigned features and functionality.
This will allow the Agile team to innovatively identify
solution details without the burden of excessive micromanagement.
Kanban does not provide sufficient rigor to manage such a complex project,
and XP will be a bit of overkill for a project like socialkare.gov.
The transformation to XP requires considerably more rigor in structure,
and XP is too software centric and heavy for socialkare.gov.