In this lesson, we talked about the value of Agile frameworks.
We discussed how an Agile framework takes
the abstract principles of the Agile Manifesto and gives it a practical shape.
We then looked at the important characteristics of the Scrum framework,
which is by far the most common Agile framework
in use across various industries globally.
We saw how the three Scrum principles of transparency, inspection,
and adaptation help Agile teams creatively manage the work with the focus on delivering
complex adaptive product features in an age wherein
customers expect rapid responses based on emerging market needs.
We proceeded to examine the important characteristics of
the Kanban framework with its original lean product development.
Kanban is a lightweight Agile framework with considerable flexibility.
The final Agile framework we looked at was XP.
A powerful Agile framework with its roots in software development.
We discussed XP stringent and strong focus on
technical excellence and best practices in software development.
We finished up by talking about some of the challenges of adopting the XP framework.
In this lesson, I hope you saw how an agile framework
allows an organization to execute on Agile's lofty promise.
This is the promise of a truly unique flavor and
that Agile focuses on both delivering quality,
and value to the business in an adaptable manner.