Agile is taking the product delivery market by storm.
Its principles relate to simplicity,
adaptability, and the ability to embrace change has a wonderful oeuvre.
Yet for Agile to practically be utilized effectively,
it is highly recommended that
a particular Agile framework or combination of frameworks be adopted.
The guidance from these Agile frameworks are based on
several years of successful implementation in
numerous organizations around the globe who have successfully delivered
complex and adaptive product results within defined constraints.
A lot of the lessons learned from these experiences have been
documented into best practices in guides,
books, and websites compiled by leading experts on specific frameworks.
From a resourcing perspective,
organizations are able to attract specific expertise from skilled agilists in
the market who have
a particularly strong background and passion for one of the specific frameworks.
Several renowned global Agile in industry bodies,
such as the Project Management Institute or Scaled Agile,
regularly publish case studies outlining in
detail the successful implementation of a specific framework.
This allows Agile transformation consultants and leaders to learn
from the experiences of other organization's Agile transformation journey.
They all adhere to the Agile mindset as being
fundamental to the success of any Agile journey.
Again, an Agile mindset is a set of attitudes supporting an Agile working environment.
When we talk about an Agile mindset,
we include respect, collaboration, continuous improvement,
iterative learning cycles, mastery and ownership,
focusing on delivering value,
and adaptability to change.
While all Agile frameworks outline how to do Agile,
they emphasize that being Agile is a key foundation to successfully doing Agile.
Some organizations in Agile teams unfortunately,
just focus on doing Agile.
This equates to simply adopting
the Agile framework's practices without
committing to a exhibiting Agile principles and values.
The Agile manifesto's four paired core values
and its associated 12 guiding principles set
a solid foundation for the various Agile frameworks that are currently being
practiced by successful organizations in today's digital age.
Again, as agilists, we regularly have to remind
Agile organizations of the core roles and their responsibilities.
With the product owner being the voice of the customer and product champion,
the facilitator as a servant leader,
ensures the team functions as smoothly as possible.
The close-knit Agile team is responsible for determining
how to get the work done that the product owner has prioritized.
When I interact with those who are new to Agile,
it's a little hard for them to initially comprehend
the abstract principles of the Agile Manifesto.
This is where the various Agile practice oriented frameworks step in.
They provide particular guidance on how to bring
the Agile Manifesto's core values and principles to life.
A framework allows an organization to execute an Agile's promise of
a truly unique flavor and that it focuses on delivering
both quality and value to the business in an adaptable manner.