Let us look at how seasoned Agilers, approach Agile frameworks.
As an Agile transformation expert,
I envision these frameworks as the enablers that
bring to fruition the good intention of an organization's leaders,
as well as Agile team members.
It brings some comfort to everyone involved to follow
a prominent framework that has been tried and tested in the market.
Agilers leverage a framework to deliver on some of the significant promises of Agile.
This includes, as the Agile Manifesto states,
focusing more on the individuals and interactions.
The organization must bring to life the theoretical appreciation that
the most significant impact on the success of
an Agile team are the skilled team members themselves.
All Agile frameworks emphasize that the ultimate determining factor for
success of a product are the resources on the Agile Product Delivery team.
How do we do this practically?
We have to recruit and retain the right skilled resources,
and cultivate a collaborative and value-driven environment
that elevates the human spirit,
to bring out the best in each resource for the collective benefit of all.
While Agilers look at a proven track record of accomplishments when recruiting,
they also look at the right team-oriented mindset
and willingness to adapt to meet the business' emergent needs.
Such a recruit, who is a flexible and collaborative team player,
when given the right environment,
propels an Agile team forward in the right direction.
As they say, if it's working well, don't over-fix it.
Leaders have to regularly be reminded that adopting Agile is supposed to improve
performance and deliver more value
directed at the product and, ultimately, organizational vision.
Each of the Agile frameworks allows for some flexibility,
so it is important to not impose everything Agile
all at once on a team that's already performing well in delivering value.
In fact, high-performing teams are quite likely to
already be engaged in many Agile practices without even realizing it.
Such high-performing teams can be gradually introduced to additional Agile practices,
based on a specific Agile framework,
through retrospectives and other guided, continually improvement opportunities.
The potential of an Agile team only
grows when they are challenged to find opportunities for improvement.
The quality of the stories that are brought into the backlog is important.
Agilers work with product owners to ensure
the users' toys have been sufficiently refined for the Agile team to proceed.
Now, a PO has to be reminded that it is
not their job to zero in on a specific technical solution.
That is the Agile team's responsibility.
A PO who heavily intrudes into solutioning
will inhibit the Agile team's innovative drive.
Transforming teams into an Agile mindset is hard enough.
A lack of respect for the backlog's priorities and
realistic estimates can drive the Agile team and everyone else crazy.
Agilers focus on ensuring that the Agile team does
not over-commit to what can be accomplished in each iteration,
especially during the first few iterations.
A close eye must be kept on the product backlog board,
with the help of a regularly updated work tracking system such as JIRA, ADO, or Rally.
At the end of the day,
implementing a specific Agile framework is a fine balancing act.
Organizations must be willing to adapt,
based on each organization's unique culture and context.
Experts have to regularly remind both leaders and the Agile team
to remember that there is no one way to execute Agile practices in an organization.
Agile principles and practices are,
by their very nature,
to be adapted as needed.