Agile has come to be an umbrella term for
a variety of frameworks that align with the agile manifesto.
The Agile Manifesto drives the Agile mindset shared
principles that are universal and encouraged across all the frameworks.
Under the Agile umbrella,
at the heart of every Agile product development in a complex environment is that
one invincible idea that someone in the business thinks is a sure win for the market.
However, history has taught us that a product and its features need to be adjusted along
the way to genuinely become
that great invincible solution that the market will fall in love with.
The.com bubble around the turn of the century taught us
the harsh lesson that if we're not willing
to be adaptable based on the pulse of the market,
our products can very quickly become irrelevant to end users.
Every Agile team's goal is to deliver value driven functionality with built-in quality.
There's the inspirational desire to deliver upon
that great idea that customers love and to do it quick.
So how should Agile teams deliver both amazing product features that delight customers,
as well as do it fast?
One way to make this happen is to quickly change course when it is
realized that a product feature is heading down the wrong path.
That is what the Agile world refers to as failing fast and learning.
With a limited amount of resources,
the longer it takes for an organization to
realize that a particular idea is not a true winner,
the more resources are wasted.
The significant advantage of failing fast is that if
a customer does not provide positive feedback for functionality being built,
the Agile team can quickly readjust
their priorities and focus on other more important items.
Enlightened and directed trial and error is what
the growth mindset promotes when it comes to fail fast and learn.
An absolutely key driver behind anything Agile is to deliver value.
Each Agile Framework, which we will be discussing,
is driven by the goal of delivering maximum business value.
It is aligned with the organization's vision.
A continual improvement process,
also often called a continuous improvement process,
is an ongoing effort to challenge everyone involved
to improve the product features or processes being used to deliver the product.
Agile promotes incremental improvement to minimize resistance from all who were involved.
Ultimately, flexibility is one of the foundations of any Agile framework.
Identifying opportunities for flexibility in
the processes and the adaptive planning that Agile frameworks
promote allows the Agile team to adapt to changes
and still have the strong capability to deliver a valuable product.
Agile frameworks promote trust and respect because
such trust and respect motivates Agile teams.
All the framework state that Agile team strive to deliver what they have committed to.
In fact, trust and respect are really the foundation for all Agile frameworks.
All Agile frameworks encourage Agile teams to cultivate mastery.
In Agile teams, time is put aside for learning and growth.
This allows Agile team members to sharpen their skills.
This built-in structure to hone their skills,
further motivates the Agile team and additional valuable results are produced.
This mindset of continual improvement is built-in alongside built-in quality.
Under the Agile umbrella,
there are large number of ever-growing frameworks some are listed here.
They include the ones identified here, plus many others.