In this exercise, you are asked to identify three benefits of using
an Agile framework and explain how
those benefits will help SocialKare.gov achieve its goals.
Let's look at my response.
Each Agile framework has grown out of the real life experiences of
professionals who did not want to be
limited by the challenges of the traditional waterfall approach.
So SocialKare.gov would benefit from the years of experience that
a proven framework has been built upon and further
refined over time at many organizations globally.
Such real life experiences will help
SocialKare.gov learn from the mistakes made by other Agile teams,
such as launching a feature without getting proper user input.
By using a proven framework,
there's a higher level of predictability for the organization.
For example, SocialKare.gov leadership and Agile team
both will benefit from defined ceremonies and defined roles for
the Agile team that make it easier to go through an Agile transformation
knowing that this has been tried and has worked for other organizations.
By adopting a proven Agile framework and its associated practices,
organizations benefit from higher quality product delivery.
SocialKare.gov will be able to deliver solutions in a timely manner with
a significantly higher level of end user satisfaction
because Agile Frameworks have quality built into each product deliverable iteration.
This prevents expensive delays due to
defects and rework at the end of the development cycle.
Another key benefit of any Agile framework is that it allows for customizing,
adapting the framework to better align with the organization.
Much like any organization,
the unique nature of SocialKare.gov product development environment will tend to lead to
some tailoring to better fit SocialKare.gov specific processes.
This refinement is best done once SocialKare.gov has tried out
an Agile Framework in its original form for awhile and learn from it.
That was my solution.
How does your answer differ from mine?