Let us look at the important characteristics of the Scrum framework.
Scrum is by far the most common Agile framework in use across industries globally.
In Scrum, the Agile team creatively manages the work with a focus on delivering
complex adaptive product features in an age when
customers expect rapid responses based on emerging market needs.
The features are delivered iterations known as sprints,
without compromising on quality.
In fact, quality is built into the Scrum framework.
Scrum prescribes a model in which a self-directed and self-organized Agile team,
plans their work themselves in a decentralized manner.
The Agile team conducts daily standups
in which they provide updates to each other every day.
They deliver in short sprints and they identify
opportunities for improvement through retrospectives at the end of each sprint.
The Scrum framework introduces specific roles with recommended responsibilities.
Scrum also introduces ceremonies with the recommended agenda, duration and frequency.
Several the Agile artifacts are regularly used in scrum.
We will look at them in a few minutes.
Now, let us look at scrums pillars and values.
Scrum is based on three pillars and five fundamental values.
Transparency in scrum refers to explicitly giving visibility to all involved,
such as the business users,
the organization's leadership, the product owner,
as well as the Agile team itself.
In order for transparency to work effectively,
scrum recommends that significant aspects of the product of
the reprocess should be defined by a common standard.
This will help everyone in having a consistent understanding of what is being observed.
Such transparency builds trust and openness,
both within the Agile team as well as with those stakeholders outside the Agile team.
Inspection involves the business users or
their representatives reviewing the Agile teams progress
towards the defined goals and objectives.
This needs to be done with some frequency,
with the recommendation being that's such an inspection
should take place at least once per sprint,
but not so frequently that it slows the Agile teams progress.
This helps with quickly identifying any unwanted variances from the defined sprint goals.
With adaptation, scrum encourages Agile teams to
adjust and adapt based on opportunities for improvement
that are identified either by the Agile team
themselves or through feedback from others outside the Agile team.
Adjustments could include process improvements if it appears that
the existing process will negatively impact the final product deliverables.
Such adjustments should be proactively
dealt with to reduce further divergence from the goals.