Now, let's look at the Scrum values.
There are five Scrum values.
They are, focus, courage,
openness, commitment, and respect.
Let's discuss each one of these Scrum values.
Delivering product features and results is a collaborative effort in Scrum,
that requires everyone to focus on
the work to be completed in order to deliver the sprint goals.
Focus. Much like all the Scrum values is derived in Scrum from the Agile manifesto.
In Scrum, members of the Agile team need to have courage to
do what is right to ensure that the sprint goals are met.
This may include having the courage to dig deep into
challenging problems being encountered and work through them.
Openness is key to Agile team performance.
The Scrum team and stakeholders agree to a culture of openness.
This ensures everyone will be comfortable to openly discuss all the work underway,
as well as any obstacles and challenges they may arise.
Commitments, build trust within the Agile team members,
and perhaps more importantly with the business users and leaders of the organization.
Scrum encourages the Agile team to have a reasonable good faith approach
to negotiating the sprint goals and
sincerely strive to attain the committed sprint goals.
Essentially, every Agile team member in Scrum,
personally committed to accomplishing the goals.
Respect is a key foundational element in Scrum for a high achieving Agile team.
The Scrum framework states that respect elevates
the Agile team members participation by including them
in ceremonies and all key planning components.
This increases the Agile teams motivation.
So does Scrum makes sense with all projects?
The answer is a clear no.
We discussed the Stacey diagram in an earlier lesson.
As the Stacey diagram shows,
an Agile framework like Scrum works best with
complex and complicated projects and products.
When there is near certainty on both the requirements and process upfront,
then there may not be as much value in utilizing Agile principles.
Scrum is also not a magical solution for chaos.
That is, Scrum cannot miraculously bring value to an environment,
where there's no vision and no clear roadmap.
Again, Scrum also does not really make a lot of sense for
simple predictable projects and products where the need
for iterative learning and adapting is of no value.