In this exercise, you are asked to recommend how you would set
up the Scrum framework for the socialkare.com product delivery team.
You were asked to include the core roles to be filled,
the Scrum ceremonies to be conducted,
and finally, the schedule and duration of the ceremonies as well as their agenda.
Here are my responses.
The three core roles in a Scrum framework are the are PO,
Scrum Master and Agile Team.
Let's start with a Scrum master role.
This role is responsible for facilitating the Agile Team's work,
obtaining resources for it,
and protecting it from problems.
The Scrum Master is servant leader to the PO and Agile Team.
The next core role in Scrum is the Product Owner.
The Product Owner represents the SocialKare.gov
stakeholders and specifically is known as the voice of the customer.
This is the one individual who's responsible for
the prioritize work item list called a product backlog.
This role is SocialKare.gov will be responsible for prioritizing the backlog,
share business decisions in a timely manner,
and is responsible for providing any requirements or
functionality related information to the Agile Team in a timely manner.
The next core role in Scrum is the Agile Team member.
Agile Team members are responsible for the creation and delivery of a system.
This role at SocialKare.gov will primarily include developers.
However, all other Agile Team members will also be included in this category.
This includes, but is not limited to,
those who will conduct modeling, programming,
testing, front-end design, business analysis,
release activities, and others.
In the retrospective, there's an opportunity for
the Scrum team to inspect itself and create a plan for improvements.
Team member discuss what went well during this sprint,
as well as opportunities for improvement.
This occurs once per sprint and is time-boxed to three hours per sprint.
In the project vision ceremony,
the business articulates a business need that is intended to
be achieved where they discuss the goals,
who the sponsor is,
what the vision is,
they clearly identify the success criteria as well as the assumptions and risks.
The project vision ceremony occurs once per project and is time-boxed to one hour.
In release planning, the organization develops a release plan that
defines when various sets of
usable functionality or products will be delivered to the customer.
They discuss critical dates and milestones,
a coordinated with dependent systems and balanced business value versus quality.
Release planning occurs once per release and is time-boxed to 20 minutes.
In the sprint planning ceremony,
work to be performed in the sprint is planned.
The agenda includes creating a sprint backlog,
planning out the tasks,
and estimating at the task level.
This can occur a few times per sprint,
but is time-boxed to a total of eight hours per sprint.
In the daily stand ups,
the Agile Team synchronizes activities and creates a plan for the next 24 hours.
Each team member answers three questions.
What did they do since the last time we met?
What do I plan to accomplish today,
and what impediments am I encountering.
The daily stand up is held daily,
preferably in the morning,
and is time-boxed to 15 minutes.
In this sprint review and demo,
along with the demo,
the Agile Team discusses marketplace changes and the backlog with the PO.
The team presents the completed sprint deliverables to
the product owner based on acceptance criteria and the definition of done.
This occurs once per sprint and is time-boxed to four hours per sprint.