Let us examine the important characteristics of the Kanban framework.
Kanban has its origins in lean product development,
an approach to product development inspired by
lean manufacturing principles and practices at Toyota.
Let us first delve into lean product development.
Lean product development focuses on seven fundamental principles.
The lean principles of eliminate waste,
build in quality, create knowledge,
defer commitment, deliver fast,
respect people, and optimize the whole,
set the foundation for Kanban.
To eliminate waste, it must be recognized and identified.
So what is waste exactly?
Waste is anything that does not add value to
the customer or anything that does not improve the quality,
and anything that unnecessarily increases
the amount of time or effort to produce the product.
Traditional product development focuses on finding defects.
Lean focuses on good practices to ensure integrity and prevent defects.
Lean encourages both training and peer-to-peer knowledge transfer to create knowledge.
In Lean, iterative demo to the business users
allows the team to live through the concept of do a little,
show a little, learn a little.
Collaboration enhances sharing of explicit and tacit knowledge.
Lean recommends the Agile team wait until the last responsible moment to make a decision.
The last responsible moment is that point
where if the Agile team does not make a decision,
you will either significantly impact the work
or a decision will be made by others for them.
The last responsible moment allows for the Agile team to
remain agile and to have some stretch of innovation.
Lean encourages the Agile team to create product incrementally where
the team builds only what is truly needed and avoids unnecessary features.
Lean recommends to release product earlier to get feedback from the customer sooner.
The Agile team needs to feel trusted and
valuable to be able to think and solve problems for themselves.
They need authority to effect outcomes.
Product development involves interdependencies with business partners,
customers, and IT departmental units.
Lean encourages decreasing barriers to increase efficiencies,
to decrease the amount of hand-offs,
and to decrease work-in-progress,
also known as WIP.
When lean principles are followed,
customer satisfaction and quality increases while the time to market is reduced.
Kanban in Japanese refers to a signboard.
This Kanban board is instrumental in Kanban.
An approach where the Agile team can visualize the workflow is
important since it helps in organizing,
tracking, and optimizing the work.
Kanban recommends establishing limits to the work the Agile team has in progress.
Kanban establishes and respects the team's ideal work capacity.
Limiting WIP helps to smooth the flow of work,
reduce lead times, improve quality,
and deliver more frequently.
By monitoring and measuring the flow of work through each work state,
issues are identified as soon as possible.
This helps to minimize lead times and improve delivery predictability.
Establishing policies that provides the Agile team with
explicit understanding of the processes has tremendous benefits.
Most importantly, discussions around issues
can take place in an objective rather than in an emotional manner.
The Agile team must own the team's work related processes
and work collaboratively to improve the processes being utilized.
A Kanban board plays a valuable role since it
articulates the work items in their various stages of the product development journey.