First things first, let's discuss the
essence of what the cover letter is, and
why it's worth your time to write
a custom letter for each application.
Employers like cover letters because
they provide information about you that
other materials can't convey.
My interests vary, and
I use a cover letter to weave
a narrative between my
different work experiences.
Which on the surface normally don't
relate to the job I'm pursuing.
The story I tell in my cover letter
usually begins with stating why I'm
excited and passionate about this job.
I've then connect how my seemingly
unrelated work experiences actually
are very relevant for the job duties and
why this prepares me for the job.
I also let the employer know I don't
want this job just to have a job, but
because I want to build my career.
I let them know what I'm most
interested in about the job and
how this will help me become
a better employee in future, and
to fulfill my short and
long term professional goals.
When you submit a general letter,
or a letter written for
another company to another employer it
doesn't portray these important nuances.
If you don't submit a targeted letter,
then you are submitting
an ineffective job application.
Give yourself the best chance you
have at getting an interview and
think critically about your application.