Now that we've explored
the value of a cover letter,
let's detail the integral
components in one.
A cover letter has one page, and
addressed to a hiring manager.
It should be succinct, captivating, and
made up of a few memorable paragraphs.
To begin writing your letter,
you first need a job to target it to.
Then you write an introduction,
two or three body paragraphs and
the conclusion.
Find a job that interests you.
You can pick a job you're
already well qualified for, but
we recommend picking your ideal job.
Even if you need to develop more skills
before you can effectively pursue it.
Going with this later option allows
you to pinpoint areas you still need
to practice for or learn.
It will also teach you to
make a case for yourself.
To show that even if you don't meet all
the job requirements you're a capable
and fast learner who can pick up new
skills quickly and deserve a chance.
Look at the job description and
take note of the skills you have,
the skills you are exceptionally good
at, and the skills you may not have.