Start off your letter by
writing the introduction,
which should include your purpose and
professional mission.
Your cover letter should include
the name of the organization and
the title of the position you
are applying to in the first paragraph,
usually the first
sentence of the letter.
This is a small detail
that goes a long way.
It helps the hiring manager's sort
through the amount of applications they
receive.
And helps the reader automatically
connect you in the job.
If you know someone in the company,
don't be afraid to ask them to refer
you, you can mention their name
in the first paragraph too.
You should focus less on why
the company should want you and
focus more on why you want the company.
This is vital on helping you stand
out among other job candidates.
If most applicants to
the job are qualified for
it, it means they all probably
have a similar set of skills.
Your statement of interest is
personal and unique to you.
The best employees are the ones who
are excited about the company, so
communicate that excitement and
be specific.
Here are a couple examples of how
to write your professional purpose.
If you're interested in
applying to Udacity.
A strong statement could be I am a self
taught web-developer eager to use my
five years of experience to
support the next major revolution
in online education.
Or if you are interested in applying
to a job within an accounting company,
this phrase could be more appropriate.
I am a passionate data analyst
fascinated by the opportunities created
by the abundance of available data and
the computing power in
the modern accounting industry.
All jobs in companies are different, so
you need to take a different
approach to all of them.