Next, we're going to do body paragraphs.
I divide these paragraphs
into categories and
different functions the job requires.
When writing your letter,
you want to focus in on things
you are especially good at.
If you are an expert at one thing,
the employer can make a logical
conclusion that you can learn and
become an expert in something else.
If the job asks for skills that you
don't have and don't show up in your
resume, use the cover letter
to make a case for yourself.
For example, let's say I am pursuing
a data analyst role which asks for
three years of experience
in data science.
But my only experience is from
taking the Nanodegree program.
But I think I could really
succeed in this role.
I would spend some time writing about
how important data-driven results and
decision making are to me.
And talk about my most advanced
Nanodegree projects that required
the most programming and
data science skills.
Your cover letter should also
include details about your relevant
qualifications and goals.
This means that you should
include concrete examples
of your related experience.
Let's dive deeper into this.
For example, a sentence such as I've
built a variety of web applications for
many audiences is vague.
And someone can already assume
this by looking at the skills or
experience section of your resume.
Instead, describe an experience such
as I recently built a website for
members of a national organization.
Some of the website features
include an appointment scheduler
that factors in time zone differences.
And a searchable online
drive of meeting notes.
This shows that you can develop
multiple types of website features,
that you can meet
the needs of the client and
that you can develop with user
experience or interface design in mind.
You should definitely expand on this
by describing which languages or
frameworks you used.
Having even just one specific example
that describes how you work and
what you can accomplish is
better that having five
general sentences about your skills.
You'll also want to give examples on
when you achieve a lot of great success.
Or when you work on a team or
with challenge to produce something
you have never done before.
Your body paragraphs are also a great
place to re enforce your goals and
how they align with the position.