Before you submit your cover letter,
remember to make sure
the formatting looks nice.
Your goal here is to make your
letter as easy as possible for
a recruiter to read.
We recommend using clear,
professional fonts.
And do not cram a bunch of
words into a small space.
When you have a lot to say,
I understand the urge to
decrease the size of your margins or
font size to fit in more words.
Doing this may not help you.
Your letter may look like a long essay
that the recruiter may not want to read.
Use standard or 1 inch margins.
I also recommend you align all
paragraphs to the left of the page, or
justify them to show structure.
Beyond the font and
spacing of your cover letter, you also
want include the following elements.
Include the date, month day and year,
in the upper right or left hand corner.
Include a formal address in your letter.
This should be to the recruiter
if the name is available.
If the name is not available,
writing dear engineering team,
depending on the team
you'd be working on.
Or dear recruiting team works too.
Be sure to include a formal
closing salutation,
such as regards Sebastian Thrun.
Lastly, I also recommend using
the same header you have for
your resume to be a header
in your cover letter.
This shows consistency and
looks really nice.