There are thousands upon
thousands of jobs out there and
searching through them
can be exhausting.
What we'll focus on now is how
to search for jobs effectively
to reduce the amount of stress and time
you'll spend on each job application.
While you're searching for jobs, you
should know what you want, research to
understand what your employer wants,
and be open to opportunity.
Knowing what you want and only searching
for roles that match these requirements
makes it easier for
you to find the right jobs for you.
It eliminates a lot of
job search fatigue, so
you don't burn out with applications or
during interviews.
Before you begin a job search,
write down two or
three things you cannot compromise on.
For example,
your requirements may be location.
You and
your family may not be able to move.
Another is company mission.
You want to do work you're proud of.
Another important one is the role.
This may seem obvious, but making
a distinction between the jobs you could
do and the jobs you want to do will
keep you motivated in your job search.
If you can't think of any requirements,
ask yourself if you'd be happy in any
job, even if its in a location you
don't want to live in, even if its for
a company whose mission
you're not passionate about.
Although being open to anything may seem
like a good thing, to the employer it
may seem like you are not committed or
excited about their company.
There is a balance between being
flexible and being focused, which is why
it's so important to create a targeted
job application and get feedback from
others, so you can see how employers
might perceive your career profile.