An effective resume is
targeted to a specific job.
An employer needs you to tell
them what you're looking for,
and then they're going to match
your resume to the job description.
You need to make this process easy for
them by having concise resume
that directly connects to
what's being asked for the job.
Even if you're uploading your resume
to a job board it still needs to be
targeted to a specific job role,
otherwise you may not
turn up in searches.
I have a one-page resume
that I work on continuously.
Whenever I apply to a job, I make
a copy of that resume and tweak it.
Sometimes I rearrange things to
emphasize certain skills are for others.
Sometimes I'll rewrite a bullet
point to make it more relevant.
Remember that a resume is meant to
be the first step in getting a job.
There will be opportunities later
on such as during your interview
to expand on any of your experiences.
A resume is a one page summary of your
professional background which includes
jobs, and projects,
education and skills.
A resume is not
the summary of your life,
things like your hobbies
should be left off.
You do not need to include extraneous
information like your references
because this information is
requested later on in the process.
When building your resume,
keep the scenario in mind.
Imagine you are applying to
the same job as five colleagues.
Briefly on paper your
resumes may look the same.
So how can a recruiter
pick whom to interview?
Since your individual
experience is unique,
focus on what might make you stand out.
Now, let's go through each
section of a typical resume.
Don't worry so much about order, you'll
be provided with rubrics later on.