Not all job applications are the same,
but they all require a resume.
It's not something you work on for
only 30 minutes and leave it at that.
You should continually build and
refine it throughout your career.
I love editing my resume.
I've worked on my resume every now and
then for
years, and
it's really motivating for me to see
how I've grown in my career whenever
I add new experiences or skills.
Every resume will be unique.
However, there are still industry
standards you have to meet,
depending on the type of job.
The industry standards we'll
discuss in this lesson,
are specific to careers in the US and
Canada.
But even if you don't want a job in
these countries, this lesson will still
be valuable for you because of
the techniques you learned,
which are applicable to all resumes.
Don't get caught up in the differences
between what a resume looks
like in the US or
what it looks like in Germany or India.
For example, in the US,
it's not normal to have a picture or
a marital status on your resume.
In Germany, it is normal.
This is not what you should focus on.
What will be important
are the techniques you'll learn to
communicate something very complex,
your professional and educational
experiences, in a concise manner
that is targeted to a specific job.
Changing the personal information
in your resume to fit
different country's standards is easy.
Distilling three years of work into
four short bullet points is not easy.
And that is one of the many topics
we'll cover in the resume lesson