When describing your work experience,
which includes your projects,
you'll want to portray three things.
One is action.
An employer only wants you if you can
complete work assignments, multitask,
and deliver results.
That is why your bullet points
should begin with action verbs.
Second is numbers.
Whenever you can,
describe your work quantitatively.
This is the best way to provide
evidence of your skills.
Leading a team of ten people is more
impressive than just leading a team.
Producing work that brought a 30%
increase in revenue is more impressive
than just increasing profits.
The third is success, sometimes you
can't attach numbers to where you work.
Perhaps what you did
was not quantifiable or
the work you did is classified.
However, you can always
showcase success,
even if you didn't achieve
what you wanted to.
Improving efficiency is a success.
Trying something new and
learning from it, is a success.
So, after you draft your bullet points,
ask yourself if they portray action,
numbers, and success.
You'll be able to see the difference,
even if it's subtle.