Once you have the content
down on your resume,
it's time to do some quality control.
Make sure it looks nice.
There are a lot of templates online
which are linked to in the classroom and
available in the career resource
center that you can use.
You can also design your own.
A nice resume design let's the reader
focus on the content of the resume.
When there are inconsistencies, such
as misalignment, and weird colors, or
formatting, the reader's eye is instead
focused on these design errors rather
than on the words on the resume.
The same logic goes to making
sure your links are clickable and
there are no spelling errors.
Typos and
design errors give the impression that
you don't have attention to detail.
And you never want an employer
to think you don't pay attention
to the small things.
Submitting a resume as a PDF will ensure
your formatting is preserved regardless
of the document reader.
Make sure your resume is one page.
Employers will not read
past the first page, so
if you have anything important on
a second page, it will be ignored.
There are certain cases where a job
candidate can have a second page on
their resume because they have years and
years of relevant industry experience.
If you don't have that
extensive experience,
keep your resume to one page.
The best way to know if your
resume design is good and
that you don't have any errors
is to have other people,
such as your friends and family,
read it and give their perspective.