Welcome to foundations of Agile and Agile frameworks.
My name is Dr. Hasnain Rizvi,
and I will be your instructor.
I am delighted to have you on board.
A little introduction about myself.
Like many agilelists, I started my career in traditional project management.
My first foray into Agile was in southern California back in early 2011.
Coming from a traditional project management mindset,
I initially thought Agile frameworks were a little
impractical for large projects in old school organizations.
I have since been proven wrong many a times.
I've had the good fortune of growing in the Agile space over the last decade.
I've been involved in complex Agile transformations across the globe,
including North America, the Middle East, Europe, and China.
I'm currently consulting as
an Agile transformation coach for a Fortune 100 company in America.
I love to teach,
and I'm an adjunct instructor and
professional trainer with several universities and organizations,
including the University of British Columbia,
Southern Alberta Institute of Technology,
Steinbeis School of International Business and Entrepreneurship,
as well as Leoron Professional Development Institute.
I have trained and mentored over 25,000 professionals across the globe.
I'm regularly invited to speak on
key Agile topics at professional events in North America,
Europe, and the Middle East.
Finally, I have a doctorate in Project and Program
Management from SKEMA Business School in France,
where my research was focused on Agile project management.
Again, welcome aboard, and I wish you all the best in this exciting course.