We will start off with discussing why Agile has taken today's digital economy by storm.
We will focus on the Agile mindset and how it sets the tone
for being Agile versus just doing Agile.
The Agile Manifesto and how it is seen as the foundational set of
four-paired core values and
12 principles that sets the foundation for all Agile frameworks.
We will wrap up the "Why Agile" lesson with
an important discussion on Agile versus Waterfall approaches.
This will explore where it makes more sense for
an Agile approach and where we are better off taking a more Waterfall approach.
We will then build upon the foundational principles of Agile,
and take a deep dive into Agile teams
and their ability to deliver immense business value.
Here, we will cover the key topics of
the key characteristics of high performing Agile teams.
The three core roles that are generally seen as universal across Agile frameworks.
We will also cover the size, structure,
and cross-functional or T-shaped skills in an Agile team.
We will cover best practices based on guidance from global experts.
Finally, we will conclude the lesson with a discussion on Agile governance.
This will include the importance of
non-core roles to the success of Agile product delivery.
We will also cover centralized versus decentralized decision-making.
The last lesson will cover Agile frameworks.
We will begin with an overview of Agile frameworks in general,
and how each of them leveraged
the Agile manifesto four-paired core values and 12 principles.
We will see how Agile frameworks are
the practical vehicle for enabling Agile and successful teams.
After this, we will cover three of
the more popular Agile frameworks being utilized across all industries.
We will first discuss the Scrum Framework,
and the benefits organizations gain when adopting Scrum.
We will then move on to Kanban,
one of the more lightweight frameworks,
and discuss its key characteristics and benefits.
We will discuss where it makes sense for Kanban to be incorporated into the workflow.
Finally, we will cover extreme programming,
which is typically called XP in the industry.
We will go over XP's core values and
strict practices along with explaining where XP should be used.
By the end of this course,
you will be able to identify and apply the characteristics of
Agile to implement value-driven delivery in these dramatically uncertain times.
Determine the appropriate Agile framework for
a specific business use case and Agile team.
Apply appropriate Agile practices for the specific Agile framework being used.
This will allow us to see how the conceptual values and
principles of the Agile Manifesto are practically implemented.
Build and evolve a high-performing Agile team.
We will understand how such high performing Agile teams become a source
of spectacular endurance for organizations with a growth mindset.
Differentiate between team roles and responsibilities of a typical Agile team,
and assign team members to an appropriate role.
By the end of this course,
you'll be familiar with many terms like the ones listed here, plus many more.