Much like other paradigm shifts in the business world,
Agile came into existence based on a business need.
Agile emerged almost organically as a result of a market
need to deal with the crisis product development faced in the 1990s.
Back in the 1990s,
it was taking somewhere in the range of two to four years to get
a software solution to production from
the time it was conceived as a valuable business need.
This delay was just not acceptable for enterprise business users.
The market had started to evolve and it was beginning to be realized that
both the needs and expectations from
the business users would not remain static for 2-4 years.
Change was inevitable before the product made it to market,
which was difficult to maneuver with the traditional product development models.
A growing number of experts felt that there had to be a better way to build
products with a focus on business users and business value.
In the spring of 2000,
a group of industry experts gathered in
Oregon to come up with some common ground on how to move forward.
This meeting would eventually lead to a famous gathering in Utah over a long weekend in
February 2001 where 17 thought leaders finalized and formalized the Agile Manifesto.
This historic meeting paved the way for
a common base for all Agile frameworks going forward.
We'll talk more about the Agile framework in the next lesson.
But for now, you should be aware that these 17 experts sought ways to
quickly build working solutions and get it into the hands of end-users.
This fast delivery approach provided a couple of important benefits.
First, it enabled users to get some of the business benefits of the new solution quicker.
Second, it enabled the product development team to get rapid feedback on the solution.
Because Agile was developed for software development,
a lot of people think that software is the only place where Agile is valuable.
This is far from the truth.
Today, Agile principles are being applied in all industries across the globe.
In the revolutionary world of Agile,
if your processes are not continually being
challenged to deliver additional business value,
you are an outdated organization.
As we will discuss in this course,
that razor sharp focus on business value is the secret to Agile's miraculous success.