There are a number of valuable agile tools in the market,
such as Microsoft Teams, Jira, Confluence,
Trello, Slack, Kanbanize, VersionOne,
Rally, and many others.
These agile tools are an excellent communication and collaboration resource.
For example, they help track progress,
iteratively assign work, track defects, plus much more.
The tools help monitor the team's progress in a transparent and visible manner.
Majority of the tools are customizable to accommodate
Agile Teams in various industries with various agile frameworks.
Agile tools make cross-functional teamwork and collaboration easier.
Whether it is pre-planning with the product team
to getting user feedback from the customers directly,
the agile team works together in one platform to deliver valuable results.
Agile tools provide real-time dashboards and
reports that show the Agile Teams progress against the product roadmap.
This helps Agile Teams better estimate capacity for future iterations.
When used properly, agile tools help
elevate and Agile Teams effectiveness and efficiency to deliver value.