In this foundations of Agile and Agile frameworks course,
you will work on a project where you will
apply the skills you have acquired in this course to
step into a business case as an Agile consultant to help launch their Agile journey.
The client in this business case is WorldVisitz.
WorldVisitz is a travel agency who is planning to launch a mobile application product.
WorldVisitz executives have hired you as an Agile consultant.
Your job is to define an Agile delivery solution to
transform the current traditional product development processes.
After being provided additional details,
you will be asked to prepare two presentations.
One will be for the executives and the other presentation will be for the team itself.
In the executive Agile transformation presentation,
you will discuss how WorldVisitz can benefit from Agile.
You will also explain to the executives which
Agile framework is best for WorldVisitz needs.
Your goal in the Agile transformation presentation is to onboard the team.
You will explain how WorldVisitz can benefit from Agile.
You will set up the team for success,
including assigning team members to roles and
establishing the ceremony structure for the framework you have recommended.
This is going to be an exhilarating project in which you will get an opportunity to take
the concepts covered in this course and
apply them with a practical lens in the Agile World.
After this project, you will be confidently
prepared to embark on your journey as an Agilist.