Now let's take a quick look at all we covered so far.
We started the lesson with setting a mindset of maximizing value for the client,
and how that is key to a freelancing carrier.
Then we discussed different channels to source clients.
Specifically discussed more about freelancing
platforms which are quite handy in starting a freelancing career.
We learn different aspects of creating
a profile and walk through a freelancing dashboard.
Lastly, we discussed best practices to send expression of interest to potential clients.
Good job so far.
In the next lesson,
we'll discuss what to do when a client does show interest in working with us.