As I mentioned previously, we want our
code to be easy for anyone to dive into.
Your users may need to use
your code to make changes or
to understand how to use it,
predictably, so might your coworkers.
And while it may surprise you, you
are also an end user of documentation.
You of the present and you of
the future are two different people.
And future you will not remember
every little detail about your code.
Treat future you just like
you'd treat a coworker, and
give them the things
they'll need to succeed.
I'll touch more on that in just a bit.
But let's first take a look at how some
of the engineers here at Udacity use
documentation.